so hi my name is Joe brewer and this is
my video for the shuttleworth fell
fellowship application process the
project that I'm proposing to do is to
create a research center on culture
design now to give a little bit of
global context for this as you're
probably well aware there are a number
of converging systemic challenges
confronting humanity in the world today
so we have the global ecological crisis
we have massive inequality and poverty
we have rigged financial systems there's
a lot of propaganda and manipulation of
public opinion there's money interest in
politics you know their whole set of
systemic issues and one of the
challenges that makes it difficult to
address all those issues is to have an
integrated and well synthesized
understanding of how cultural systems
change in time so I've been working for
more than 15 years on a number of
different projects as you'll see in my
resume to bring together all of the
different Sciences that study cultural
change and bring them under under one
umbrella and I'm calling this work
culture design so the design of culture
is seeking to intentionally change the
trajectory of civilization right now
with the convergence of systemic crises
in the world the human civilization that
we are living in is to put it mildly
it's at jeopardy our prospects for
making it through the resource scarcity
the ecological crises the various social
issues we have with governance openness
and accountability we're not solving any
of those things quickly enough and if
we're going to have a thriving complex
civilization and a hundred years from
now we will only get there if we do it
by design so basically here's the very
specific thing that I'm proposing to do
I want to create a Research Center
affiliated with a university that begins
to bring together the different fields
of research from three key areas those
three key areas are
complexity science so this is the study
of nonlinear adaptive systems phase
transitions emergent phenomenon network
science a host of related things like
what you would see done at the work of
the Santa Fe Institute the second one is
cognitive cognitive science and cultural
evolution together which is looking at
the way that the human mind works
through the lenses of psychology
anthropology linguistics computer
science and other related areas and
cultural evolution looking at the
evolutionary history of human social
nature the group dynamics of humans how
that applies to organizational
development to marketing and
communications to storytelling to whole
host of areas so and these are the first
two so the third one is global change
global change being really an earth
system science perspective looking at
how climate is changing how the global
biosphere is changing how the complexity
of human systems is changing so these
are all areas where a great deal of
research is done in a reductionist
disciplinary manner at the present
moment there are actually hundreds of
research fields looking at different
pieces of this problem but none of them
are focused specifically on bringing
together all of the pieces that are
necessary to guide civilization through
the transition to sustainability and
this is a global research capability
that is needed to both study the
patterns of culture and how those
patterns of culture are rising and other
changing and also to guide them through
effective policy tools and those policy
tools can be governmental like taxation
and regulation and those sorts of things
that are familiar but they also can be
in terms of decision-making structures
which gets into the world of social
entrepreneurship innovative business
models disruptive social technologies
which could be computer technology or
ways of group facilitation or
storytelling transmedia experiences a
variety of ways this can come through
but as i said earlier in this all of
this knowledge in the hundreds of
different fields looking at this problem
are disparate from each other the
institutions of society from which they
came in business government and academia
are all
siloed and separate from each other and
there's a great need for synthesis so if
I win this if you award me this
fellowship what i will do is convene a
conference you can think of it as like a
three-day workshop of the leading
scholars and practitioners in the field
of culture design to map out the
landscape of best practice and deep
knowledge across the different fields of
knowledge that are in the academic world
as well as in design practice and then
begin to build an institutional capacity
for researching things like how do we
achieve peace in a world that is
troubled by resource scarcity how do we
keep dictators from arising and fear
based approaches from winning out in our
political struggles how do we reduce the
amount of chronic and equality in the
world and create a more vibrant
innovation capacity and resilience in
our infrastructure these core issues
that will only be achieved by bringing
together all the pieces so that's what
I'm setting out to do and I've already
made a lot of headway have a number of
strategic partnerships a global network
of collaborators and what I'm needing
now is the financial resources to
convene the meetings and begin building
the nonprofit research organization that
will deliver these goals and these
results so that's it thank you very much
for your time and I look forward to
hearing back from you